The importance of AndroidManifest.xml
AndroidManifest.xml is an important file for any application that wants to be published on the Google Play Store. It contains important information about the application, such as the permissions required, the SDK used, and the device configuration. In this blog post we'll take a look at some of the most important characteristics of AndroidManifest.xml.
The contents of AndroidManifest.xml
AndroidManifest.xml
The file AndroidManifest.xml is the key to understanding how an Android application works. It defines the essential information required for the build tools and the Google Play Store.
The file contains a lot of important information, but some of the most important are:
- The application's name and package name 
- The permissions required for running the application 
- The device configuration needed for running the application 
- The hardware and software requirements needed to run the application
The permissions required for an Android application
When creating an Android application, a number of permissions must be defined in order for the application to function. In this article, we will look at the permissions required for an Android application and how they are defined in AndroidManifest.xml.
The first permission required for an application is access to the device's camera. This permission is defined in the section of the manifest file using the tag. The permission can be granted to any Activity or Service that needs it, as long as that Activity or Service is defined as requiring it in its own Manifest file. In our example project, we have a MainActivity class that requires this permission and requests it on behalf of all other Activities and Services that need it.
The next permission required by our application is access to the phone's contacts and calendar data. This permission is also defined in the section of the manifest file, using the tag again. The tag specifies that this permission is required by all Activities and Services that need it.

